# **MANIKUMAR M**

manikumar4493@gmail.com



9488109979



O Coimbatore, India 642110

With a strong background in electrical engineering, extensive hands-on experience and a deep understanding of Electrical performance diagnostics, I am confident in my ability to contribute effectively to your engineering team and ensure the highest standards of quality and performance of your products. To seek and maintain full-time position that offers professional challenges utilizing interpersonal skills, excellent time management and problem-solving skills. Electrical Engineer familiar with all major engineering standards associated with electrical components.

#### **SKILLS**

- Good understanding of Electrical Drawings, Planning of Projects, Erection & Maintenance.
- Both practical as well as theoretical knowledge of Different Electrical Instruments.
- Working more efficiently and productively so that maximum output comes.
- Product Testing, Team Leadership, Staff Management, Electrical Engineering Standards

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### 12/2022 - Current

# ELECTRICAL ENGINEER - LAKSHMI ELECTRICAL DRIVES LTD, Coimbatore, TAMILNADU.

- Motor testing (squirrel cage induction motor) as per specification is 12615:2018 & IEC/EN 60034-1
- Handling Variable Frequency Drive (Danfoss)
- Validating the current design and performance of the motor w.r.t to all models.
- Problem solving by finding RCA and 8D report (CAPA) for Customer complaints.
- Analyzing customer complaints by 5W and 3H basis.
- New product development IE4 and IE6 Class Energy Efficient induction motor's & Reluctance motors.
- Preparing Control plan and SOP for concern department.
- Handling Testing team and plan shift and schedule and work allotment based on FIFO.
- Knowledge in Electrical panel.
- Preparing the CAPEX document for new Test bed and Developing new Fixtures for product testing.
- Knowledge in SAP- HANA. Ability to use the SAP software suite to solve problems. Performing various operations in Testing Related process and maintaining records.
- Calibrated and repaired existing systems to maintain functionality.
- Inspected and performed validation testing for designed systems and thirdparty installations.
- Identified specific cables, fuses and circuit breakers required for assigned installations.
- Evaluated project scope to estimate costs and set timelines for project
- Improved methods for measurement, documentation, and work flowmanagement.

#### 09/2018 - 12/2022

# Jr. Engineer-Testing, ELGI ELECTRIC INDUSTRIES Ltd, Coimbatore, India

- · AC motor's and DC motor's testing
- Checking DC motor's Armature, Field and Interpole coils and AC motor stator's windings
- Supervised a team of electricians responsible for all motor's and responded to provide technical
  - assistance to electrical equipment problems within the company-owned facilities
- The ability to work well under pressure and motivation to work extra hours when necessary
  - Guided, trained, and developed the field electrical and instrumentation personnel
- Worked in External inspection -Railway inspection RDSO.
- Proposed electrical product and system modifications to improve quality and efficiency.

#### 03/2015 - 03/2016

# Graduate Engineers Trainee- VIRGO ENGINEERS LIMITED, Coimbatore, TAMILNADU

- Following predicts, preventive and breakdown maintenance of machines
- Responsible for all aspects of underground work including cable pulling, installing instruments &
  - threaded rod, tray, ladder rack, small power and lighting, terminating
- Diagnose malfunctioning systems, equipment, and electrical parts and to identify the cause of breakdown and fix the problems.

#### **EDUCATION**

- DR.NGP INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY B.E Electrical and Electronics Engineering-6.24 2014
- P.K.D MATRIC HR SEC SCHOOLHSC Computer science 68.83 2010
- SUBASH VIDHYA MANDIR SCHOOL SSLC Mathematics 73.8 2008

### **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION - CERTIFICATIONS**

#### **BIS CERTIFICATION**

- Maintaining the BIS portal and following the proper data of production value for the financial year.
- BIS Audit External inspection will be conducted and Renewal of BIS License of the company will be followed.

#### **CE CERTIFICATION**

- Acquiring CE certification fort the motors by External inspection.
- External inspection TUV NORD.
- Following all the parameters by International Standards and conformity of the Requirements.

## **DISCLAIMER**

I hereby declare that above information is true to best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: Coimbatore Sign: Manikumar.M